Sometimes we feel that the overall fold is less or more flat after we finish the costume, and we will get more fold details through some adjustments.
First, select a costume version and select the interior of the colon layer, and then remove the face.
Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical version, and select to add to the inside.
The reason for selecting the interior of the colon layer is that the outer layer has a pocket version, and if the colon is on the outer layer, the powder line of the pocket will penetrate the version, and there will be instability.
Due to the cancellation of the connection of the inner layer, the extra inner line on the version of the colon can be deleted.
If you don't delete it, when the colon layer is automatically formed, the powder line will pull the costume, and some unnecessary folds will occur.
Since there is already a copy of the inside as the basis, we can increase the number of layers.
Use the edit text tool to select the layer, and you can see that the layer has been deleted.
In the case of the main color, you can see that the pattern is in the direction of the kill line, which is parallel to the arrow, and the golden line and the vertical is the tail.
First, we increase the tail lock rate, so that the outer layer can be widened horizontally.
Then, increase the golden lock rate to lengthen the outer layer, and since the outer layer is relatively large, there will be folds.
At the seam line, it is especially obvious, because the
seam line of pocket is still the size of the original one.
On the pleats that have more or less seam lines such as the pocket,
At this time, we can use another function, which is the ruler function.
After selecting the ruler tool, when the collection rate is positive, you can stretch the grid.
When the collection rate is negative, you can search the grid.
The pocket plates are more likely to have folds in the division and division.
Therefore, when we want the collection rate to be positive, we need to create a positive ruler along the edge of the outer plate.
Then reduce the particle distance and simulate it.
In addition, if you need a fold on the clothes plate due to the division of the pocket,
please set the inner line of the pocket to the ratio of 98 to 99.
In addition, the pocket plates of the collection are related to the joint.
Therefore, it is not possible to create a symmetrical plate directly.
You need to remove the joint first to be symmetrical.
The physical properties of the changed fabric can also produce different fold textures.
Increase the strength of the elastic band and the strength of the corner line.
The stretchability of the fabric becomes worse.
The inner layer of the clothing continues to become smaller.
The fold will be smaller.
The fold will be more easy to produce.
The overall texture of the fabric will also become deeper.
After reducing the bending strength, the fold will become thinner.
It looks deeper.
Pay attention to this part.
The original soft fold will become more sharp.
The fold will become thinner.
You need to be careful.
The unfastened order will not be smooth.
The fold will be thinner.
It is to be seen that the fold is less flexible.
Press and fold to make the fold width larger.
If the fold size is not large, it is necessary to fold it.
If the fold is small, it will not be comfortable.
It's a little difficult to lower the fold length to the shoulder.
In this way, there will be a difference in length between the front and back pieces, and there will be some small wrinkles in the front piece.
Then you can apply the ratio of 99 to the side.
There will be some wrinkles. This method is also suitable for the side of the sleeve and the side of the shirt.
Sometimes we need some dynamic wrinkles effect, so we can use the
Scenic Comparison function.
First, open a position with a larger range of motion.
Following the change of the action position, there will be some more characteristic wrinkles in the pants.
At this time, we choose the Scenic Comparison function, which will keep some of the wrinkle texture.
When you change the position to a vertical position, you can see that the Scenic Comparison version will keep some of the wrinkles.
This method is suitable for the effect of keeping some dynamic wrinkles on the static model.
After canceling the Scenic Comparison and simulation, the clothing will gradually return to its original state.
During the process, if you pause the simulation by pressing the control button, you can keep a foldable shape effect.
These are some simple ways to add foldable details.
See you in the next video.